<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
	
		Techniques for WCAG 2.0 
		Techniques and Failures for Web Content Accessibility Guidelines 2.0
		WD-WCAG20-TECHS
		W3C Working Group Note
		
			January - March
			2010
		
		
			http://www.w3.org/WAI/GL/2010/WD-WCAG20-TECHS-200100128/
		
		
			Single file version
			
			Alternate Versions of Techniques for WCAG 2.0
		
		
			http://www.w3.org/TR/WCAG20-TECHS/
		
		
			http://www.w3.org/WAI/GL/NOTE-WCAG20-TECHS-20090105/
		
		
			
				Ben Caldwell
				Trace R&amp;D Center, University of
					Wisconsin-Madison
			
			
				Michael Cooper
				W3C
			
			
				Loretta Guarino Reid
				Google, Inc.
			
			
				Gregg Vanderheiden
				Trace R&amp;D Center, University of
					Wisconsin-Madison
			
			
				Wendy Chisholm
				(until July 2006 while at W3C)
			
			
				John Slatin
				(until June 2006 while at Accessibility Institute, University of Texas at
					Austin)
			
		
		
			This section describes the status of this document at the time of its
				publication. Other documents may supersede this document. A list of current
				W3C publications and the latest revision of this technical report can be
				found in the W3C technical reports index at http://www.w3.org/TR/.
			This is a Working Group Note "Techniques for WCAG 2.0". These
				techniques are produced by the Web
					Content Accessibility Guidelines Working Group to provide guidance about
				how to conform to the Web Content
					Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) 2.0  Recommendation.
				Techniques are referenced from Understanding
					WCAG 2.0 and How to Meet WCAG
						2.0. Please note that the contents of this document are informative (they
				provide guidance), and not normative (they do not set requirements for
				conforming to WCAG 2.0).
			The Working Group requests that any comments be made using the provided online comment
				form. If this is not possible, comments can also be sent to public-comments-wcag20@w3.org.
				The archives
					for the public comments list are publicly available. Comments received on this document may be addressed in future versions of this document, or in another manner. The Working Group does not plan to make formal responses to comments. Archives of the WCAG WG mailing list
						discussions are  publicly available, and future work undertaken by the Working Group may address comments received on this document.
			Materials from the public to assist in documenting 
				techniques are particularly welcomed. Please use the Techniques Submission
					Form to submit techniques. 
			This document has been produced as part of the W3C Web Accessibility Initiative (WAI). The
				goals of the WCAG Working Group are discussed in the WCAG Working Group
					charter. The WCAG Working Group is part of the WAI Technical
						Activity.
			 Publication as a Working Group Note does not imply endorsement by the            W3C Membership.  This is a draft document and may be updated, replaced            or obsoleted by other documents at any time. It is inappropriate to cite            this document as other than work in progress. 
			This document was produced by a group operating under the 5 February 2004
				W3C Patent Policy. W3C maintains a public
					list of any patent disclosures made in connection with the deliverables
				of the group; that page also includes instructions for disclosing a patent.
				An individual who has actual knowledge of a patent which the individual
				believes contains Essential
					Claim(s) must disclose the information in accordance with section
						6 of the W3C Patent Policy. 
		
		
			"Techniques for WCAG 2.0"  provides information to Web content developers who wish to  satisfy the success criteria of Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) 2.0 . Techniques are specific authoring practices that may be used in support of the WCAG 2.0 success criteria. This document provides "General Techniques" that describe basic practices that are applicable to any technology, and technology-specific techniques that provide information applicable to specific technologies. The World Wide Web Consortium  only documents techniques for non-proprietary technologies; the WCAG Working Group hopes vendors of other technologies will provide similar techniques to describe how to conform to WCAG 2.0 using those technologies. Use of the techniques provided in this document makes it easier for Web  content to demonstrate conformance to WCAG 2.0 success criteria than if  these techniques are not used.
			Besides the techniques provided in this document, there may be other techniques that  can be used to  implement conformance to WCAG 2.0. The WCAG WG encourages submission of such techniques so they can be considered for  inclusion in this document, in order to make the set of techniques maintained by the  WCAG WG as comprehensive as possible.  Please submit techniques for  consideration using the "Techniques Submission Form."
			This document is part of a series of documents published by the W3C Web  Accessibility Initiative (WAI) to support WCAG 2.0. This document was published as a Working Group Note at the same time WCAG 2.0 was published as a W3C Recommendation. Unlike WCAG 2.0, is expected that the information in Understanding WCAG 2.0 will be updated from time to time. See Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) Overview for an introduction to WCAG, supporting technical documents, and educational material. 
		
		
			
		
		
			
				History of Changes to WCAG 2.0 Working Drafts
			
		
	
	
		
			Introduction to Techniques for WCAG 2.0
			
				This document is part of a series of documents published by the W3C Web Accessibility Initiative (WAI) to support WCAG 2.0 . It includes a variety of techniques which include specific authoring practices and examples for developing more accessible Web content. As well, it lists failures, which describe common mistakes that are considered failures of WCAG 2.0 Success Criteria.
				This is not an introductory document. It is a detailed technical description of techniques that can be used to address the requirements in WCAG 2.0. See Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) Overview for an introduction to WCAG, supporting  technical documents, and educational material.
				In order to make the set of techniques maintained by the WCAG WG as comprehensive as possible, the WCAG WG encourages submission of new techniques so they can be considered for inclusion in this document. Please submit techniques for consideration using the "Techniques Submission Form."
				
				Sufficient and Advisory Techniques
				Rather than having technology specific techniques in WCAG 2.0, the guidelines and success criteria themselves have been written in a technology neutral fashion. In order to provide guidance and examples for meeting the guidelines using specific technologies (for example HTML) the working group has identified sufficient techniques for each Success Criterion that are sufficient to meet that Success Criterion. The list of sufficient techniques is maintained in the "Understanding WCAG 2.0" (and mirrored in How to Meet WCAG 2.0). In this way it is possible to update the list as new techniques are discovered, and as Web Technologies and Assistive Technologies progress.
				Note that all techniques are informative. The "sufficient techniques" are
					considered sufficient by the WCAG Working Group to meet the success criteria. However, it is not necessary to use these particular techniques. If techniques are used other than those listed by the Working Group, then some other method for establishing the technique's ability to meet the success criteria would be needed
				Most success criteria have multiple sufficient techniques listed. Any of the listed sufficient techniques can be used to meet the Success Criterion. There may be other techniques which are not documented by the working group that could also meet the Success Criterion. As new sufficient techniques are identified they will be added to the listing.
				In addition to the sufficient techniques, there are a number of advisory techniques that can enhance accessibility, but did not qualify as sufficient techniques because are not sufficient to meet the full requirements of the success criteria, they are not testable, and/or are good and effective techniques in some circumstances but not effective or helpful in others. These are listed as advisory techniques and are right below the sufficient techniques. Authors are encouraged to use these techniques wherever appropriate to increase accessibility of their Web pages.
				
			
			
				Technique Collections
				The following list includes links to a series of techniques document collections. 
				
				
					Techniques for WCAG 2.0 (includes all techniques and failures as a single file)
					General Techniques
					HTML and XHTML Techniques
					CSS Techniques
					Client-side Script Techniques
					Server-side Script Techniques
					SMIL Techniques
					Plain Text Techniques
					WAI-ARIA Techniques
					Flash Techniques
					PDF Techniques
					ARIA Techniques
					Common Failures
				
			
		
	
	
		
		
		
		
		
		
		
		
		
		
		
	
	
		
		
			References
			
				"Cascading Style Sheets, level 1," B. Bos, H. Wium Lie, eds., W3C Recommendation 17 Dec 1996, revised 11 Jan 1999. Available at http://www.w3.org/TR/REC-CSS1/.
				"Cascading Style Sheets, level 2," B. Bos, H. Wium Lie, C. Lilley, and I. Jacobs, eds., W3C Recommendation 12 May 1998. Available at http://www.w3.org/TR/CSS2/.
				"Cascading Style Sheets, level 2 revision 1,"  B. Bos, T. Çelik,  I. Hickson,   H. Wium Lie, eds., W3C Candidate Recommendation 25 February 2004.  Available at:  http://www.w3.org/TR/CSS21/
				
				
					[CSS 2.1 and CSS 3] Roadmap, CSS WG's table of modules and publication dates.
				"Flash", Adobe Systems. Available at http://www.adobe.com/devnet/swf/.
				"HTML 4.01 Specification," D. Raggett, A. Le Hors, I. Jacobs, eds.,  W3C Recommendation 24 December 1999. Available at http://www.w3.org/TR/html401/
				
				"PDF", Adobe Systems. Available at http://www.adobe.com/devnet/pdf/.
				"Web Content Accessibility Guidelines 2.0,"  B. Caldwell, M Cooper, L Guarino Reid, and G. Vanderheiden, eds., W3 Recommendation 12 December 2008, http://www.w3.org/TR/2008/REC-WCAG20-20081211.  The latest version of WCAG 2.0 is available at http://www.w3.org/TR/WCAG20/.
				
				"XHTML 1.0 The Extensible HyperText Markup Language (Second Edition)," S. Pemberton, et al.,  W3C Recommendation 26 January 2000, revised 1 August 2002. Available at:  http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/.
			
		
	
